GILLIAN YEOMANS

Full-Stack Developer

Portfolio: gillian.tech

Github: yeo-yeo

LinkedIn: gyeomans

Email: gillian@yeomans.org.uk

I am a former Risk Analyst, retrained as a Full-Stack Developer. I love learning new skills and technologies, and putting them to practical use with my business experience. I am based across London and Rome and enjoy yoga and crosswords.

EXPERIENCE

Founders and Coders, London

18 week full-stack selective bootcamp with a focus on strong fundamentals (e.g. vanilla JS) and project work. Emphasis on pair programming and team mentality. TDD, agile and continuous integration tools used throughout.

The course culminates with a 3-week project for an external product owner: see details overleaf.

British Institute & My English School, Rome

English teacher working with individuals and groups of all ages and all levels: beginners, conversation, business, secondary school exams.

Nephila Advisors, London/Bermuda

Risk Analyst specialising in Nephila's Lloyd's insurance syndicate 2357, in team of 5 overseeing \$330m of GWP. My roles included financial modelling of natural catastrophe impact, operational liaison, underwriting analysis. I developed a number of processes and tools which are still in use 3 years after my departure.

Lloyd's of London

Graduate Programme in Lloyd's insurance market: rotations in Research, Market Analysis and external placement to Nephila syndicate 2357 in Bermuda.

STACK

2019-2020 **FE/BE**

HTML
CSS
JavaScript
TypeScript
React
Node.js
PostgreSQL
GraphQL
Airtable

2017-2019 **TESTING**

Jest Tape NYC Codecov

2015-2017

2013-2015

TOOLS
Git
Travis
Heroku
Netlify
AWS

DESIGN

Figma Adobe XD

GILLIAN YEOMANS

Full-Stack Developer

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh

First Class MA (Hons)
English Literature and Classics
Roy M. Pinkerton Prize in Latin

University of Washington, USA

International exchange Annual Dean's List Meg Greenfield Essay Prize

PROJECTS

Chatti

DevOps Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Airtable

Brief description of what Chatti is. 3 person team - shared scrum master role

www.chatti-app.herokuapp.com

Signpost

QA Lead / Developer

HTML, CSS, React, Javascript, Express, PostgreSQL

Brief description of what Signpost is. Implementation of Google map and Geocoding APIs Testing and code coverage

www.signpost-app.herokuapp.com

VOLUNTEERING

Code Your Future, Rome

Codebar

Crisis